# Deepjyoti **Chakraborty**

IT Project Manager, PMP, AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

Address Ahmedabad, India, 382210

**Phone** +918511891443

E-mail

chakraborty.deepjyoti@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/deepjyoti

-chakraborty-



Experienced Senior Project Manager with PMP and AWS Cloud Certification ready to provide strong technical direction and strategy development to Agile and DevOps teams across development units. Keen abilities in business management including budgets, scheduling, and business development. Success in B2B and B2C and client management. Highly technical experience in Business Intelligence (BI) with sound knowledge on SQL, various BI Tools (SSIS, SSRS, SSAS, SAP BO).

### Skills

Planning and Coordination	Excellent
Client liaison	Excellent
Project Scheduling	Excellent
Cost Control	Excellent
Problem-Solving & Analytical	Excellent
Data Modelling	Very Good
DW Architecture & Design	Very Good
Data Management, Analytics, Migration	Very Good

## **Work History**

2018-01 - Current

# **Senior Project Manager**

HHAeXchange, Ahmedabad, IN

- Developed project plans and managed project scope using methodologies to guide projects from conceptualization to implementation and maintenance.
- Directed changes to project scope and cost and implemented appropriate change management processes to keep project on track.

- Finalized project financial records while collaborating with financial controllers and executives.
- Worked with third-party vendors to streamline appropriate processes
- Collaborated with business users, technical teams, database administrators and testing teams during kickoff meetings, joint application designing and planning sessions to validate requirements.
- Monitored contracts and service level agreements to identify potential risks and implement mitigation actions to protect development process from unforeseen delays and costs.

### 2011-05 - 2017-11 **System Engineer**

IBM, Neuchatel, Jakarta, Kolkata, Switzerland, Indonesia, India

- Resolved issues and escalated problems with knowledgeable support and quality service.
- Proposed technical feasibility solutions for new system designs and suggested options for performance improvement of technical components.
- Spearheaded compliance efforts and developed best practices to drive continual process improvements.
- Worked with stakeholders to determine implementation and integration of system-oriented projects.
- Created flowcharts, diagrams and other documentation.
- Documented system configuration, mapping and processes.
- Checked for accuracy and functionality during implementation of new systems.
- Automated data collection activities to increase productivity.
- Worked as Onsite/Technical Coordinator at various client Sites to manage Customers
- Configured, installed and upgraded SQL databases.
- Designed, coded, tested, debugged and documented programs using agile development practices.

## 2008-07 - 2011-05 Lead Software Engineer

RMS (iQor) India Pvt. Ltd., Gurgaon, Noida, India

- Translated customer and system requirements into robust software design with test-driven approach.
- Developed code using SQL and other programming languages to support digital repository frameworks and integrate systems.
- Worked on SSRS Reporting Services to build reports
- Worked on SharePoint (Admin) to deploy and subscribe reports for the customer
- Reviewed project specifications and designed technology solutions that met or exceeded performance expectations.
- Wrote relational database queries for stored procedures, query optimization

and performance tuning.

- Delivered technical guidance and consultation with application teams, clients and developers for technology domain environments.
- Provided guidance and direction to less experienced staff in resolution of highly complex technical problems.
- Worked collaboratively with stakeholders to resolve technical roadblocks.
- Communicated project plans, tracking details, status updates and risk mitigation plans to cross-functional team.
- Managed project and personal schedule by consistently meeting deadlines.
- Delivered unit-tested systems within customer-prescribed timeframes.
- Collaborated with clients to define solution requirements.
- Worked extensively in Datwarehouse architecture, design and implementation using various BI tools

### Education

#### 2006-09 - 2008-07 M

# Master of Technology (2 Years Post Graduate Degree): Information Technology

Dr. B.R Ambedkar University - Agra

#### 2002-09 - 2006-07

# Bachelor of Engineering (4 Years Graduate Degree): Electronics And Communications Engineering

Visveswaraya Technological University - Belgaum

# **Accomplishments**

- Delivered the biggest Project in my carrier so far, AWS Cloud Migration. Migrating all OnPrem Apps and servers successfully and timely into AWS Cloud.
- Received Client satisfaction award from both the Client locations (Neuchatel and Jakarta) by delivering beyond expectation results.

Award Name: Above and Beyond the Call of Duty

## Certifications

2022-04 Project Management Professional (PMP)

2022-03 AWS Cloud Practitioner

## **Additional Information**

Currently my Canada PR process is on the verge of getting final approval. ITA was issued and electronic submission of documents done on 3/14/22. Waiting for final approval / PR VISA Letter.

• Express Entry Profile #: E002646221

Nomination Certificate #: 3062335